[Music]
welcome to yellow brick road I'm Jordan
this is James and today we're gonna talk
about what's really gonna happen to
Julian Assange now obviously we don't
know but john kérékou might have an idea
but first please consider donating to
Devon's journey to recovery the link is
in the description box
it's a GoFundMe link for Devon's journey
to recovery this is for charity it's not
for us we don't personally make any
money off of this it is to help pay
someone's medical bills cuz we don't
have free health care so please donate
Devon's journey to recovery GoFundMe
link is down all right so I saw this it
was recommended to me by an algorithm
it's redacted tonight and they get an
interview with John kérékou he is I
believe former intelligence type guy you
know whistleblower prosecuted went
through the whole [__] process and he
might understand what's gonna happen to
Julian Assange as much as anyone else
because he had to go through it so
here's John Carriacou with Li camp
discussing what's gonna happen to Julian
Assange speaking of Julian Assange
you've done an incredible job of
covering the persecution of Assange on
your show load and clear and we don't
need to go through every detail of it
because you know I've done a lot of that
but one part that you're uniquely suited
to talk about is if he weren't
extradited to the US with the US once
what kind of trial would he get here in
the US I don't think he would ever go to
trial I think that the deck is so
stacked that that it's just not it's not
within the realm of possibility for him
to receive a fair trial what we're
talking about here is the Eastern
District of Virginia this is the the
federal court that's based in Alexandria
Virginia there's one judge there in
particular judge Leonie brinkema she was
appointed to the bench the federal bench
by President Reagan
she was elevated from magistrate to
trial judge by President Clinton and
before she became a judge she was a
national security prosecutor in the
Justice Department
so she reserves all national security
cases for herself she did my case she
did Jeffrey Sterling's case she has the
Snowden case she has Julian Assange's
case she even took Zacarias Moussaoui
the alleged what was it the 20th
hijacker no national security defendant
has ever won a case in her courtroom she
made it clear to me in the very
beginning to my attorneys that she would
not allow us to put on a defense we
actually made 70 separate motions asking
that 70 separate classified documents be
declassified so that I could present
them to prove my innocence we blocked
off two days for that hearing and we
walked into the courtroom and she said
I'm gonna make this easy for everyone
and I'm gonna deny all 70 of these
motions and then that was it as we were
walking out of the court my seeing you
so you you're not allowed to basically
present evidence it's like you're done
for there's nothing you can do it's over
for you
if you can't present [__] evidence
and I think he's gonna say where it's
it's just held up in court for years
sort of like like Chelsea Manning right
she won't speak
she won't uh you know she won't say
anything and he's closed room [__]
courtrooms so I just say oh well hold
you in contempt for years at a time
let's let him continue seventy of these
motions and then that was it as we were
walking out of the courtroom I saying
you can't have any evidence you can't
have a defense and and that's exactly
what's gonna happen in Julian Assange I
said to my lawyers what just happened
and they said we just lost the case
that's what happened I said well what do
we do now the answer was now we talk
about a plea that's so incredible
and that's also interesting you're not
allowed to present evidence so it's like
you're already trapped in a corner and
the best I can hope for as far as they
have any sense of a normal life after or
any type of freedom is to take a plea
deal now what happens with the plea deal
you accept guilt even if you may not be
guilty so now to New York Times and
Washington Post and Rachel Maddow can
say I told you so
pleaded guilty to hacking the election
if Assange does that what she probably
won't hmm that's what I'm guessing I'm
guessing he won't do it you won't accept
guilt which means they're gonna throw
him in jail forever and ever and ever
I might happen either way but no plea
deal means it goes to trial you have no
evidence I mean I understand this you're
like [__] random movies from the 90s
where it's like it's okay if you don't
plead guilty we'll go to trial if we go
to trial they're gonna put death penalty
on the table like that [__]
there's also peers under under a
specific circumstances I believe you can
plead guilty but it's not because you
admitted guilt yeah it's out of the for
your own well-being just say that I got
no contest something like that and you
get sent to jail anyway
yeah I know yeah
it's usually you know I don't think
that'll be on the table well I think
it's either we probably we convict you
in which case you're guilty or you admit
you're guilty and get less time I guess
in which case we got we wanted you were
guilty of being a Russian hacker Oh
actually that's what the newspapers or
so because this case isn't about the
2016 election it's about the Chelsea
Manning video mmm it's more about that
so you're guilty of
hacking our computers or something to
get you know D like secret information
from the US military
what the newspapers will probably twist
it and to rushing hacking see he's
hacked before so he's definitely hacking
yeah we just can't build the evidence
against him but we know he did this so
we're gonna probably turn it into that's
type of story let's let them keep going
well then yeah and then in your case
they pushed you into this plea deal and
then they wouldn't even let you take out
all this stuff in the plea deal that
wasn't true oh my god isn't that nobody
focuses on that I'm so glad that you
brought that up so in the plea deal they
have this this final agreement and it's
the prosecutors that write the agreement
so you can object and they can tell you
to go fly a kite
and so in this agreement it has me
confessing to grave crimes right that I
didn't commit and I said to the judge
she asked me if I had anything to say
and I said yeah I have something to say
my lawyer says no no he doesn't he
doesn't I said no I do it so I got up
and I said to the judge this is all
nonsense I didn't do any of the stuff
that they're that they've put into this
agreement well she says it's just window
dressing and I said be that as it may
it's simply not true the same things
gonna happen to Julian so even though
throw extra charges in there that so
they will get them on the Russian
hacking the 2016 election thing they
will get them on that by just adding it
to the charges and then that's if he
pleads guilty which you probably won't
in which case we'll just convict them of
it or off something this is unfair
completely unfair it's unfair to
everyone actually it's really unfair for
Julian but it's unfair for everyone else
as well at this type of world exist it's
a sad thing
right here that's incredible I mean so
amazing
and this also gets to to what's going on
with Chelsea Manning yes well in terms
of miscarriage of justice Chelsea
Manning is in prison right now for not
going along with this grand jury just
talk about that and talk about the
reason she's given for not going along
Chelsea Manning has been hit doubly in
this case Chelsea was subpoenaed to
testify before a grand jury we now know
that that was Julian Assange's grand
jury she refused to testify and she was
locked up in contempt of court so what
happens when you are in contempt of
court is that you have to remain in jail
until you change your mind or until the
term of the of the grand jury runs out
well that term ran out after something
like 62 days I think it was and they had
to release her well then they rien
panelled a grand jury looking apparently
for four additional charges that they
could levy against a Julian Assange it's
like they're trying to pressure her into
saying something she hasn't said
absolutely and see that's the key what
she said this was her defense is you
don't need for me to testify because I
already testified in my own case and all
you have to do is take the transcript
and submit it as evidence into the grand
jury and I said no we want you to repeat
yourself with the idea being if she were
to contradict herself
they can they can put a false statements
felony charge on her and then use that
as additional pressure to get her to
actively testify against Julian she
wouldn't play their game which was
really really brave now what she could
have done was take the easy way out she
could have said I don't recall you just
sit there in front of the grand jury and
in response to every single question you
say I don't recall but she didn't she
said you are not going to force me to do
anything I don't want to do and she was
willing to give up her freedom for it
yeah and now they're and now they're
saying that she owes after 30 days $500
a day followed by 60 days $1,000 a day
and it's you know it tortured my
chequebook basically I think that may
actually be unconstitutional it's
something that certainly her attorney to
take up fuck-fuck the constant
Oshin it's immoral straight-up all that
[__] and then they bill you after
thousand dollars a day you owe us
what do you spend that money on he's
feel it [__] his ass backwards man
that's completely unfair and I'm not
surprised that might be bad too that
only does Chelsea Manning go to jail do
the time get pardoned goes back to jail
and I did there'd like trying to keep
her in jail that's very weird like
having her come in to repeat the same
words again
to like catch them on something like
these people are hard hard to call
people there's gum it's like empty shell
people and I wish I had more details on
it I wish I had more details on like who
these people are cuz he's he's naming
Nate he named that judge I already
forgot her name but he named that judge
like who is this person
what's up with them can I can I find
video on his person and I read try to
read their psyche like why says months
ago it's specific a specific place where
they're all these whistleblowers are all
brought and they all get they all get
convicted well they all get you know
it's just a big [__] ass either way
yeah whistleblowers are high-profile
cases like he said xx you know yeah
bomber or whatever on 9/11 oops I said
bomb yeah very weird it's sort of like
remember like you know you hear Jimmy
door your progressive types talk about a
name near attend and then you actually
hear speak
and it's like whoa like do you drink
virgin blood or something like she strap
looks like a witch I'm not gonna lie
just like Hillary very similar mmm in
those regards it's like what's going on
in your psyche or what's not going on in
your psyche the freak but I don't want
to completely dehumanize them they
shouldn't be completely dehumanized I'm
sure there's a scared child hiding
somewhere in their hearts but uh that's
so that's another problem how many
people are equipped to deal with such a
thing not many not the Dalai Lama that's
for [__] sure
and anything else to say on this that's
it from us just wanted I just I heard
this clip and I was like what the [__]
and just one things without researching
them seem unfair and you get one more
detail and it's like it's even more
unfair than you thought it was before
it's probably even worse than these guys
are even saying they're not they don't
they didn't take time to go go about the
whole [__] thing I mean if I don't
know what to say
there should be some sort of HBO
documentary or something but I don't
think they would do that I'm 50 about
fifty years later
yeah after everyone's dead and gone
that's it for most please subscribe you
feel like comment agree disagree I don't
know why you disagree we didn't really
say much recommend videos on any topic
that's always cool it's helpful donate
Devon's journey to recovery the GoFundMe
link is down there description box and
with all that said give this video a
thumbs
say you want to get him
[Music]
[Applause]
surprise
[Music]